Erdni Zergetaev

zergetaev@gmail.com +79962590913 Moscow

Summary

Full Stack web developer with 5.5 years of experience. Built a few successful projects from scratch. Worked on huge websites with millions of users and legacy codebase. I understand both the technical and the product side of an online business.

Open to remote contracts and visa sponsorship proposals.

Work experience

CTO

rabota08.ru • Elista 09/2021 - Present

- Launched the MVP which gathered 500+ daily clients
- Formulated the business model with multiple revenue sources (selling ads and pro features) with the CEO
- Integrated APM and Error Tracking Software

Senior Full Stack Developer (remote)

Bonfire • San Francisco, California

05/2021 - Present

- Implemented an airdrops feature on blockchain which helped to attract dozens of new creaotrs
- Built a B2B dashboard for content creators
- Refactored parts of codebase, increased test coverage with Jest, added granural typings which allowed to fix many financial bugs
- Built a solid archectural foundation, based on Next.js, PostgreSQL, redis for caching and Amazon SqS for background jobs

Senior fullstack developer (remote)

Busbud • Montreal, Quebec

08/2019 - 05/2021

- Added support for selling train tickets, which greatly increased the amount of sold tickets
- Made a russian version: collaborated with translators, designers and marketers to adapt the website to the local market, laws and partners
- Refactored parts of legacy codebase with TypeScript, signifcantly improved test coverage with Jest, which reduced the tech debt and allowed to iterate much faster

Stack: TypeScript, Express.js, React.js/Redux, Jest, PostgreSQL, Docker.

Full Stack Developer (remote)

Vayable • San Francisco, California

05/2019 - 08/2019

- Migrated legacy codebase from Rails 3 to Rails 5
- Moved to a React.js frontend, which allowed for many QoL features and improved performance
- Added JSON API for said frontend and partners
- Significantly improved test coverage with Rspec, FactoryBot and Capybara, which helped to fix many bugs and sped up the development process

Full stack developer

Krypton Capital 12/2017 - 05/2019

jury.online - an escrow platform for safe investments in blockchain startups. During my tenure the project has successfully raised more than 3 million dollars in investments.

- Developed a web dashboard for Ethereum smart contract. Worked with Solidity developers to integrate smart contracts via Metamask Browser extension.
- Developed a JSON API with accompanying Swagger documentation.

Selected Accomplishments:

I was the only developer responsible for developing the dashboard in time before the ICO, and I have succeeded, helping the project to raise more than 3 million dollars in Ethereum investments.

Tech: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, React.js, Web3.js, Webpack, Rspec, Capybara

buzz.im - a platform for advertising in Telegram messenger. Responsibilities:

- Optimized performance to achieve 90+ scoring on Google PageSpeed Insights
- Worked with the developers of telegram bot to integrate its capabilities into the platform
- Developed a JSON API with accompanying Swagger documentation, which is used by Vue.js frontend
- Worked with with designers on mockups for a design revamp, integrated the resulting HTML & CSS into the platform.
- Helped the marketing department with their job by improving SEO and creating helpful metrics with Metabase.

Stack: Ruby on Rails 5, MySQL, Bootstrap, StimulusJS, jQuery, Rspec, Capybara

Fullstack web developer

Freelancer 02/2016 - 12/2017

Professional Skills

- Rails
- Redux
- PostgreSQL
- Docker
- Node.js
- Bootstrap
- Next.js
- Web3

- React
- TypeScript
- Rspec
- Jquery
- GraphQL
- Stimulus.js
- Ethereum

Education

Entrepreneurship

Russian Business Leaders 2021

Russian Business Leaders is a US State Department program for young Russians engaged in business leadership positions to gain exposure to work in the US private sector.

Bachelor's degree in Information Technology

Graduation project, called "Processing and analysis of the results of expert evaluation of a set of alternatives aka Delphi method " had received an excellent mark and was featured on local TV.